Card Mounted Photographs P025 P025
Stage
Card Mounted Photograph Collection
1883-1889
Stage
P025
1 box
Custodial History
Images transferred from the Washington Historic Image Collection in 2006. There is no deed of gift and it is uncertain as to how the library acquired the majority of these photographs. A few images do note donor on the rear of the image.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 33 albumen card mounted portraits. These types of images come in a wide variety of styles and sizes. Among the more popular were the cabinet card and carte de visite (CDV). The majority of the images where mounted on standardized mounts roughly measuring 4 ¼" x 6 ½" for cabinet card and 2 ½" x 4 ¼" for the CDVs. In addition to these formats there was also an assortment of larger decorative mounts that gained popularity during the Victorian era. The image itself is often an Albumen print, which is a process by which the emulsion was developed on very thin sheets paper, and was then pasted to the cardboard mounts.
Photographs
- Series 1
  - Allen, Clarence G., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Negative Number: 519
  - Beall, Seward - With bicycle, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Negative Number: 848
  - Bontelle, John, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Negative Number: 846
  - Bowerman, Mrs. George F., Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Burnett, Charles - With bicycle, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Negative Number: 847
  - Byrnes, Ed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Negative Number: 844
  - Caldwell, Charles H. - Baby, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Negative Number: 822
  - Cleveland, Grover - With Allen Thurman and US Capitol, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dean, E. C., Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Negative Number: 794
  - Dodge, Charles R., Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Negative Number: 795
  - Evans, John A. - In uniform, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Negative Number: 796
  - Fellows, H. A. - In uniform, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Negative Number: 717
  - Gill, Lancey W., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Negative Number: 687
  - Grannis, Charles G. - In uniform, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Negative Number: 683
  - Greeley, A. W. - In uniform, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hawley, C. E., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Negative Number: 953
  - Jenkins, Fred, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Negative Number: 989
  - Johnson, Fred L. - With bicycle, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Negative Number: 988
  - Johnson, Fred L. - With bicycle, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Negative Number: 990
  - Kelly, Ivan - CDV, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Killetts, J. M., Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Negative Number: 1022
  - Leaming, Joseph E., Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Negative Number: 1035
  - Littell, J. Reed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Negative Number: 1037
  - Manners, E. C., Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Negative Number: 1161
  - McCook, Charles M., Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Negative Number: 1167
  - Moran, T. Pling, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Negative Number: 1160
  - Newman, Ed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Negative Number: 8080
  - Noyes, Theodore W., Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Negative Number: 1188
  - Owen, Fred D., Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Negative Number: 1189
  - Quinn, M. J. - In uniform, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Negative Number: 1199
  - Rule, James F., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Negative Number: 1256
  - Schnider, F. F., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Sturmey, Henry, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Todd, Weber - In uniform, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Negative Number: 1283
  - Tyler, Edward Royall, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Negative Number: 1284
  - Way, Will H. - In uniform, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Negative Number: 1166